Guide to the Records of the Public History Program RG 20.9
New York University Archives
- Series VI: Multimedia
  - 1994-1999
    - Charas/El Boltio Footage, Liz Sevcenko, 3/22/1997, Tape 3 (Box 11, Object 29)
    - P.S. 122, Liz Sevcenko, 4/6/1997, Tape 1 (Box 12, Object 1)
      Barcode: 3-1142-04227311-3
    - P.S. 122, Liz Sevcenko, 4/6/1997, Tape 2 (Box 12, Object 2)
    - Yuri Kochiyama Interview, 3/21/1999, Part 1 (Box 12, Object 3)
    - Yuri Kochiyama Interview, 3/21/1999, Part 2; George Yuzawa Interview, 2/28/1999, Part 2 (Box 12, Object 4)
    - George Nagamatsu Interview, 4/2/1999, Part 1 (Box 12, Object 5)
    - George Nagamatsu Interview, 4/2/1999, Part 2 (Box 12, Object 6)
    - George Nagamatsu Interview, 4/2/1999, Part 3 (Box 12, Object 7)
    - George Yuzawa Interview Excerpts, 1999; Visuals #2 (Box 12, Object 8)
    - Fujio Saito Interview, 3/14/1999 (Box 12, Object 9)
    - Fujio Saito Interview Excerpts, 1999 (Box 12, Object 10)
    - 'NY - The Way it Was,' March 1994 (Box 16, Object 10)
    - Oral History class interview with Rose Down for Lower East Side Oral History Project, 3/24/1994 (Box 16, Object 11)
    - 'River of Steel: The Building of the New York City Subway,' Kerry Michaels and Stuart Math, Steel River Productions Inc., 1994 (Box 16, Object 12)
      Two personalized notes to Paul Mattingly dated January 23, 2002 and signed by Stuart Math accompany the VHS Cassette Tape
    - 'Signal to Noise: Life With Television, Show One: Watching TV Watching Us,' Cara Mertes, 1995 (Box 16, Object 13)
    - 'Signal to Noise: Life With Television, Show Two: TV Reality,' Cara Mertes, 1995 (Box 16, Object 14)
    - 'Signal to Noise: Life With Television, Show Three: Remote Control,' Cara Mertes, 1995 (Box 16, Object 15)
    - 'Bernice Abbott - Photographer,' PBS, 2/16/1995 (Box 16, Object 16)
    - 'Shaker Heights: The Struffle for Integration,' Stuart Math Films, 1998 (Box 16, Object 17)
    - 'Margaret Sanger', PBS, 10/15/1998 (Box 16, Object 18)
    - 'Frank Lloyd Wright, Part I,' PBS, 11/10/1998 (Box 16, Object 19)
    - 'Frank Lloyd Wright, Part II,' PBS, 11/11/1998 (Box 16, Object 20)
    - 'Midwife's Tale,' PBS, 1998 (Box 16, Object 21)
  - 2000-2007
    - 'Newark' documentary, by Mariel P. Isaacson, 1/2005 (Box 15, Object 2)
      U-matic: 3/4 in. analog, 2 VHS Cassette Tapes
    - Hudson Square Workshop, 2007, Part 1 (Box 15, Object 3)
      Verbatim DVD
    - Hudson Square Workshop, 2007, Part 2 (Box 15, Object 4)
      Maxell DVD-R
    - ITP/Public History Project: ‘Someday…’ (Box 15, Object 5)
    - Interview with David Hicks on the NYU History Department, 5/11/2000 (Box 15, Object 6)
      Hi-8 Video Cassette, SONY P6-60HMPX
    - Interview with Carl Prince on the NYU History Department, 10/24/2000 (Box 15, Object 7)
    - 'Barely Legal: Visions of the Past, Voices of the Future,' Brian W. Beaton, Spring 2001, Public History Project (Box 15, Object 8)
      The VHS cassette tape is in a Quantegy VHS cardboard case. The cassette does not have a label and the only mark on the cardboard case is the number '61977' written on yellow tape.
    - 'The African Burial Ground: Whose History Is It?", Courtney Dralwer, October 2002 (Box 15, Object 9)
      General note
      The tape is labeled "Courtney Brouwer 2-min spot"
    - 'Thunder in Guyana,' Suzanne Wasserman, 2002 (Box 16, Object 22)
    - 'Isabel Bishop: A Window on Union Square,' Sara Nolan, 10/29/2002 (Box 16, Object 23)
    - 'Post Industrial Visions of Steel,' Mariel P. Isaacson, Public History Seminar 2, Spring 2003 (Box 16, Object 24)
    - 'Coney Culture,' E.A. Durden, 5/9/2003 (Box 16, Object 25)
      Apple DVD-R
    - 'Grand Central: A Triumphant Portal,' Stephanie M. Carter, 5/12/2003 (Box 16, Object 26)
      Memorex DVD-R
    - 'Politicians and Popular Culture,' Rebecca Martin, Material Culture of American Life, 5/12/2003 (Box 16, Object 27)
      VHS Cassette Tape T-60PR
    - 'An Un-Gentlemanly Agreement: The Bates 7 and NYU,' Evan Friss and Joseph Felice, 5/2004 (Box 16, Object 28)
    - 'Networks of Transport, Networks of Influence: Alfred Ely Beach's Pneumatic Subway,' Terri Lonier, Fall 2004 (Box 16, Object 29)
    - 'Deindustrialization and Recovery,' Mariel P. Isaacson, 10/26/2004 (Box 16, Object 30)
    - 'It's All Business in Gay Times Square,' Anne Parsons, Public History Scenario, Oct. 2004 (Box 16, Object 31)
    - Public History Workshop, Tape 1, 5/3/05, 2005 (Box 16, Object 32)
      Panasonic Mini DV 60 SP / 90 LP videocassette
    - Public History Workshop, Tape 2, 5/3/05, 2005 (Box 16, Object 33)
      Panasonic Mini DV 60 SP / 90 LP Videocassette
    - 'Steeltown Hometown,' Mariel P. Isaacson, MPIFILMS, Ltd., 2005 (Box 16, Object 34)
      DVD
    - 'Creating Community in Greenwich Village,' Jenny Pachucki, Fall 2005 (Box 16, Object 35)
      Memorex DVD-RW
    - 'Lincoln Square to Lincoln Center,' Mariel P. Isaacson, Material Culture of American Life, Fall 2005 (Box 16, Object 36)
      Four (4) DVD-R
    - 'The Badlands of Manhattan?, 1 of 1,' Emily Levine, Fall 2005 (Box 16, Object 37)
      HP DVD-R 8X
    - 'La Quinta,' Maria Slena Howard, Material Culture of America, 12/13/2005 (Box 16, Object 38)
      TDK DVD-R 16X
    - 'The Road to Here...', Shira Rappaport, 12/2005 (Box 16, Object 39)
      DVD-R
  - Undated
    - Herbert Abrons Interview, No. 1, 60 min, 1990s undated (Box 12, Object 11)
    - Herbert Abrons Interview, No. 2, 30 min, 1990s undated (Box 12, Object 12)
    - Herbert Abrons Interview, No. 3, 1990s undated (Box 12, Object 13)
    - Rose and Lucy Tortorella interview, 1990s undated (Box 12, Object 14)
      It can be assumed that this oral history interview draws relation to the 1990 Public History Workshop, which explored the interactions between Chinese and Italian immigrants on the Lower East Side.
    - Rose and Lucy Tortorella interview, copy, 1990s undated, 1993 (Box 12, Object 15)
      There was a note attached to this cassette that reads: 'Henry Street Workshop,' which leads one to believe that this interview was conducted for the 1993 Public History Workshop that focused on the Henry Street Settlement House. There was, however, no date on the actual cassette.
    - Tony D'Apolito interview, copy, Tape #1 of 2, 1990s undated (Box 12, Object 16)
    - Tony D'Apolito interview, copy, Tape #2 of 2, 1990s undated (Box 12, Object 17)
    - Beethoven #1, #2, Tony D'Apolito, 1990s undated (Box 12, Object 18)
      TDK MC90 Audio Cassette
    - Beethoven #3, Tony D'Apolito, 1990s undated (Box 12, Object 19)
      TDK Maverick MC90, Audio Cassette
    - Vita Poliseno Interview, 1990s undated (Box 12, Object 20)
      Scotch BX60-90 Audio Cassette
    - Vita Poliseno interview, copy, Side A only, 1990s undated (Box 12, Object 21)
    - Anthony Rinaldi interview, 1990s undated (Box 12, Object 22)
      There is good basis to assume that this oral history interview is related to the Public History Workshop of 1990, focusing on relations between Chinese and Italian immigrants on the Lower East Side.
    - Victoria Mascato interview, 1990s undated (Box 12, Object 23)
      It can be assumed that this oral history interview related to the 1990 Public History Workshop, which focused on relations between Chinese and Italian immigrants on the Lower East Side.
    - Victoria Mascato interview, Copy, Side A only, 1990s undated (Box 12, Object 24)
    - Stonecutters Riot in Washington Square, 1834 (Box 12, Object 25)
      Contents description and attached note
      This cassette contains a documentary created by associates of the Public History program. The topic of the documentary is the Stonecutters Riot in Washington Square, 1834. The label on the case notes that 'Rich, Eileen, Joan, Rachel, and Danny' were its producers.
    - Master Edit 1, Part 1, 1990s undated (Box 13, Object 1)
      Barcode: 3-1142-04227312-1
    - Master Edit 1, Part 2, 1990s undated (Box 13, Object 2)
    - Ports Interview excerpts, 1990s undated (Box 13, Object 3)
    - J.A. Visuals #1, 1990s undated (Box 13, Object 4)
    - Master Copy #1, Liz Sevcenko, 1990s undated (Box 13, Object 5)
      Tape is blank, when played. There is no picture and no sound. Playing the tape produced a high-pitched noise from the equipment.
    - Master Copy #2, Liz Sevcenko, 1990s undated (Box 13, Object 6)
      This tape, when played, appears to be an incomplete copy of the following item in this box ('Master Edit')
    - ‘March of Time,’ by Karen Y. Rosen, Part 1 of 1, 1990s undated, The duration of this cassette is 8 minutes. (Box 13, Object 7)
      Student work
      This documentary was created by student Karen Rosen.
    - ‘Horizons’ and ‘Evening News,’ Pamela Nelson Application, 1990s undated (Box 13, Object 8)
    - Public History 3, Rich slideshow, 1990s undated (Box 13, Object 9)
      Tape Characteristics
      The first quarter of this cassette appears blank when played in the proper equipment.
    - Unknown Public History tape, 1990s undated (Box 13, Object 10)
    - Tape 2, begins with Charmaine, then J. Pento, 1990s undated (Box 13, Object 11)
      Hi-8 Metal-P Video Cassette
    - Tape 1/Tape 3, 1990s undated (Box 13, Object 12)
      Mislabeling of tape
      The case of this tape is labeled 'Tape 1,' but the tape itself is labeled 'Tape 3.' There is little else to determine the contents of the cassette.
      Maxell Audio Cassette, LN-90
    - Rehearsal #3, Oral Presentations, 1990s undated (Box 13, Object 13)
    - Workshop, Camera Tests, 1990s undated (Box 13, Object 14)
    - Tape 3, J. Pento, 1990s undated (Box 13, Object 15)
    - Tape 1, 1990s undated (Box 13, Object 16)
      Sony, Hi-8 Metal-P Video Cassette
    - Tape 1, Practice Tape, 1990s undated (Box 13, Object 17)
      Hi-8 Video Cassette, P6-30HMPX
    - ‘Margaret Sanger: A Public Nuisance,’ documentary, 1990s undated (Box 13, Object 18)
    - ‘1968’ Edits for Rachel Bernstein, 1990s undated (Box 13, Object 19)
    - ‘Americana’ Video, Tape 3, 1990s undated (Box 13, Object 20)
    - Tape 1, Juan Mendez Interview, 1990s undated (Box 15, Object 10)
    - Copy, 1/31, 1990s undated (Box 15, Object 11)
      Analog video cassette
    - Master Edit, 1990s undated (Box 15, Object 12)
      Tape format
      Tape contents
      This tape contains footage from various sources, including the previous listing ('Master Copy #2').
    - 'Afrikamerica: A Strolling Slide Show,' documentary, 1990s undated (Box 15, Object 13)
    - Public History slide show, 1990s undated (Box 15, Object 14)
    - 'Harlem's Cotton Club,' Steve Bossous, undated (Box 15, Object 15)
    - 'Union Square "Revitalized,"' Michael Shapiro, Public History, undated 2000s (Box 15, Object 16)
    - 'Heaven Will Protect the Working Girl,' American Social History Film Library, undated (Box 15, Object 17)
    - 'WPA Guide to NYC,' Mathilde Lerosier, undated (Box 15, Object 18)
    - 'Building Public Housing in New York,' Tracy Neumann, undated (Box 15, Object 19)
    - 'The Diamond District: Growing Pains,' Rebeccah Movsky, undated (Box 15, Object 20)
    - 'City Kids Meet Ashcan Art,' Robert W. Snyder, undated (Box 15, Object 21)
    - 'Beach Tunnel,' Terri Lonier, undated (Box 15, Object 22)
    - 'Fulton Street Mall: Economics, Hop-Hop, and Ownership,' Jessika G. Drmacich, undated 2000s (Box 15, Object 23)
      Two (2) DVD-R 8X
    - 'The Assimilation of a People: The Irish in New York,' Katern Murphy, Material Culture DVD, undated 2000s (Box 15, Object 24)
      Apple DVD-R 8X
    - 'Women and the Univeristy in the 1920s...', Korean-American Exhibit at the Balch Institute, Pam Nelson, Microsoct Word-Macintosh, undated (Box 15, Object 25)
      3M 3.5" Diskette
    - 'MSHome.JPG,' 1. Michael Shapiro, Public History, 2. Sarah Nolan Window, undated (Box 15, Object 26)
      IBM 3.5" Diskette
    - 'Public History Scanned Papers: NYU Workshop, Sporn, Nelson, Barnett, Mart...", undated (Box 15, Object 27)
    - 'Becoming and American in Easy Installments: Material Culture and Consumerism on New York's Lower East Side 1900-1940,' Molly Mitchell, MSWord and Wordperfect files, undated (Box 15, Object 28)
      Verbatim DataLife MF 2HD 3.5" Diskette
    - Jonathan Kovel, Director of Photography undated (Box 18, Object 1)
    - Lawrence Weschler, Tape A, undated (Box 18, Object 2)
    - Lawrence Weschler, Tape B, undated (Box 18, Object 3)